Immortal Beloved is a drama, music, romance film directed by Bernard Rose.
A chronicle of the life of infamous classical composer Ludwig van
Beethoven and his painful struggle with hearing loss.
Following Beethoven's death in 1827, his assistant, Schindler, searches for an elusive woman referred to in the composer's love letters as "immortal beloved."
As Schindler solves the mystery, a series of flashbacks reveal Beethoven's transformation from passionate young man to troubled musical genius.
Ludwig van Beethoven, played by Gary Oldman.
Anton Felix Schindler, played by Jeroen Krabbé.
Anna Marie Erdödy, played by Isabella Rossellini.
Johanna Reiss, played by Johanna ter Steege.
Karl van Beethoven, played by Marco Hofschneider.
Nanette Streicherová, played by Miriam Margolyes.
Immortal Beloved is a 1994 biographical film written and directed by Bernard Rose and
starring Gary Oldman, Jeroen Krabbé, Isabella Rossellini and Johanna ter Steege.
The film narrates the life of composer Ludwig van Beethoven (played by Oldman) in flashbacks while it follows Beethoven's secretary and first biographer Anton Schindler's
(Krabbé) quest to ascertain the true identity of the Unsterbliche Geliebte (Immortal Beloved) addressed in three letters found in the late composer's private papers.
Schindler journeys throughout the Austrian Empire interviewing women who might be
potential candidates, as well as through Beethoven's own tumultuous life.
The film explores themes of composer, deaf, letter, biography, sister-in-law.
The tone is emotional.